John Temple Papers
© 2005 University of Connecticut
John Temple Papers.
1968-1974
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Temple, John.
.1 linear feet
British poet.
MSS19980215
Biography
British Poet. Several of his poems appeared in The Magazine of Further Studies (Buffalo, NY).
Scope and Content
The collection contains letters andmanuscripts of John Temple sent to Andrew Crozier, edito of Ferry Press. The majority of the materials (1972-1974) pertain to the publication of Temple's book, The Ridge (earlier title The War Changed Me) and include typescripts, galleys, and cover proofs. Also included are annotated poetry manuscripts (1968-1972) and a letter from Jeremy Prynne to Andrew Crozier enclosing some of Temple's poems.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of literary manuscripts. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Crozier, Andrew—Correspondence.; Prynne, J.H., 1936- —Correspondence.
Subjects:
Ferry Press.; Editors—Great Britain.; Publishers and printing—Great Britain.; Authors and publishers—Great Britain.; Poetry—Editing.; English poetry—20th century.; Great Britain—Business, industries, and trades—Publishing.; London (England)—Business, industries, and trades—Publishing.; Great Britain—Cultural affairs—Literature.; Londong (England)—Cultural affairs—Literature.; Poems.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Manuscripts.; Galley proofs.
Occupations:
Poet.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Unknown.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Papers, 1968-1974
  - Correspondence
    - Prynne, Jeremy to Andrew Crozier, 1970 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
    - Temple, John to Andrew Crozier, 1972-1974 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Poems, 1968-1972 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - The Ridge
    - “The War Changed Me” TSS, 1973 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
    - “The War Changed Me” TS, 1973 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - Corrected Galleys, 1973 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
    - Cover proof, 1973 (Box 1:, Folder 7)